<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on The Dyer Laboratory</title>
    <link>http://dyerlab/categories/projects/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on The Dyer Laboratory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://dyerlab/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ERAC Spring 2016 Presentation</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/05/erac-spring-2016-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/05/erac-spring-2016-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Environmental Research Advisory Committee meeting
Virginia Transportation Research Council
The spring meeting of the VDOT ERAC is this week and Bonnie and I will be going to provide some feedback on what we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing on the project the last two months (it is pretty early yet, we are just getting going).  Should be fun, lots of cool other projects being presented.  See the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1mE_sGSiaN_0vKbz0aZfg50DjbsjCagsp5DQMu6mak44/pub?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; below the fold.
more&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So True!</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/04/so-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/04/so-true/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/04/phd101212s.gif&#34; alt=&#34;phd101212s&#34; /&gt;
Use
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;version control&lt;/a&gt; or editors in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://drive.google.com&#34;&gt;cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 0 - On iBooks Store</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/04/volume-0---on-ibooks-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/04/volume-0---on-ibooks-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/book/applied-population-genetics/id1101353809?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=11&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/04/Screen-Shot-2016-04-08-at-7.43.40-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2016-04-08 at 7.43.40 AM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Anna Tucker</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/01/congratulations-anna-tucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/01/congratulations-anna-tucker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previous Dyerlab member, Anna Tucker, just got her thesis work accepted for publication in
Auk. Be on the lookout for the following:##Opportunistic conspecific brood parasitism in a box-nesting population of Prothonotary Warblers (Protonotaria citrea)
moreConspecific brood parasitism, while prevalent in some avian taxa, is easily overlooked in when it occurs low frequencies and therefore the ecology of this behavior has been only occasionally described in passerines. Here we describe the occurrence of conspecific brood parasitism (CBP) in a population of Prothonotary Warblers (Protonotaria citrea) breeding in nest boxes, demonstrate associated fitness costs, and investigate parasite strategy. We genotyped individuals at six microsatellite loci and used CERVUS to determine log-likelihood of maternity (LOD scores) for offspring and social mothers. We set critical cut-off LOD scores at 95% confidence for exclusion of the social mother and assignment of a parasite mother from the breeding population. Of 805 nestlings (233 family groups from 2009 to 2013), we found that 12.7% had incompatible genotypes with their social mother. Females with unrelated nestlings (hosts) fledged fewer biological offspring within the host year than non-host females despite fledging more total offspring, but being a host was not significantly associated with total reproductive success over five years of breeding. We were able to identify only ~30% of parasite females, suggesting that the majority of parasites may be floaters (i.e. non-nesters) in the population or nesting in nearby natural cavities. We found no evidence of host selection based on host age, arrival at the breeding site, or nest box productivity in the previous year. This opportunistic behavior is likely facilitated by the nesting ecology of this population, in that nest sites are limited, conspicuous, and relatively dense. Future studies investigating CBP in populations using natural cavities can help elucidate the drivers of this behavior.&lt;a href=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/01/1452262898_full.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/01/1452262898_thumb.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taxonomy of Academic Sustainability</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/10/the-taxonomy-of-academic-sustainability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/10/the-taxonomy-of-academic-sustainability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Been working on a lexicographic analysis of &amp;lsquo;Sustainability&amp;rsquo; as published by the journals
PNAS and
Sustainability.  Here are the stemmed word forms for 366 published articles represented as a hierarchical clustering.  The wordclouds represent the top 10 word stems per group.
more
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2015/10/TaxonomyOfSustainability.png&#34; alt=&#34;TaxonomyOfSustainability&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dogwood mating season</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/04/dogwood-mating-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/04/dogwood-mating-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;img/dogwood_flowers.jpg&#34;&gt;Love is in the air!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
