<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>People on The Dyer Laboratory</title>
    <link>http://dyerlab/categories/people/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in People on The Dyer Laboratory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://dyerlab/categories/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Sciences Graduation</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/05/life-sciences-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/05/life-sciences-graduation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re about to be told one more time that you’re America’s most valuable natural resource. Have you seen what they do to valuable, natural resources? Have you seen a strip mine? Have you seen a clear-cut in a forest? Have you seen a polluted river? Don’t ever let them call you a valuable natural resource! They’re gonna strip mine your soul! They’re gonna clear-cut your best thoughts for the sake of profit, unless you learn to resist, ‘cause the profit system follows the path of least resistance, and following the path of least resistance is what makes the river crooked!
Utah Phillips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Dr. Viverette!</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/04/congratulations-to-dr.-viverette/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/04/congratulations-to-dr.-viverette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to the latest member of the PhD club, Dr. Cathy Viverette!  Today, she became the 14th graduate student to graduate from the lab and the very first doctoral student.  Take a break, relax, and then let&amp;rsquo;s get to those revisions!  ;-).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Anna Tucker</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/01/congratulations-anna-tucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/01/congratulations-anna-tucker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previous Dyerlab member, Anna Tucker, just got her thesis work accepted for publication in
Auk. Be on the lookout for the following:##Opportunistic conspecific brood parasitism in a box-nesting population of Prothonotary Warblers (Protonotaria citrea)
moreConspecific brood parasitism, while prevalent in some avian taxa, is easily overlooked in when it occurs low frequencies and therefore the ecology of this behavior has been only occasionally described in passerines. Here we describe the occurrence of conspecific brood parasitism (CBP) in a population of Prothonotary Warblers (Protonotaria citrea) breeding in nest boxes, demonstrate associated fitness costs, and investigate parasite strategy. We genotyped individuals at six microsatellite loci and used CERVUS to determine log-likelihood of maternity (LOD scores) for offspring and social mothers. We set critical cut-off LOD scores at 95% confidence for exclusion of the social mother and assignment of a parasite mother from the breeding population. Of 805 nestlings (233 family groups from 2009 to 2013), we found that 12.7% had incompatible genotypes with their social mother. Females with unrelated nestlings (hosts) fledged fewer biological offspring within the host year than non-host females despite fledging more total offspring, but being a host was not significantly associated with total reproductive success over five years of breeding. We were able to identify only ~30% of parasite females, suggesting that the majority of parasites may be floaters (i.e. non-nesters) in the population or nesting in nearby natural cavities. We found no evidence of host selection based on host age, arrival at the breeding site, or nest box productivity in the previous year. This opportunistic behavior is likely facilitated by the nesting ecology of this population, in that nest sites are limited, conspicuous, and relatively dense. Future studies investigating CBP in populations using natural cavities can help elucidate the drivers of this behavior.&lt;a href=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/01/1452262898_full.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/01/1452262898_thumb.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Jane Remfert</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/08/welcome-jane-remfert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/08/welcome-jane-remfert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have added a new member to our lab, Jane Remfert.  She is an incoming ILS PhD Student who is going to work on pollen movement in dogwood.  Very exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Position</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/04/new-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/04/new-position/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It looks like I will be moving into the position of Assistant Director for the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vcu.edu/cesweb/&#34;&gt;Center for Environmental Studies&lt;/a&gt; this year!   Should be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Lab Member</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/03/new-lab-member/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/03/new-lab-member/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just received verification that Jane Remfert has decided to join the Dyer lab in the fall as a new PhD student!  AND she is interested in working on dogwood!  Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
