<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gene Flow on The Dyer Laboratory</title>
    <link>http://dyerlab/categories/gene-flow/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gene Flow on The Dyer Laboratory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://dyerlab/categories/gene-flow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk at Temple!</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2016/11/talk-at-temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2016/11/talk-at-temple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Giving a talk up at Temple University, last seminar of the year but one I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to giving for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- More --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B0T81CzLjtfPbVlYTFVGVzVKUWc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dyerlab.bio.vcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/4831/2016/11/Screen-Shot-2016-11-13-at-10.30.05-PM-300x224.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen-shot-2016-11-13-at-10-30-05-pm&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the image to download a PDF version of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Population Genetics Textbook Release</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/12/applied-population-genetics-textbook-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/12/applied-population-genetics-textbook-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be posting portions of all 10 chapters of my upcoming textbook, Applied Population Genetics, as early draft chapters to this website over the spring semester.
This book will be published in both ibook and print-on-demand versions. I prefer the ibook format because I can embed interactive content (movies, JavaScript, etc.) into the text and it will update automatically when I make revisions etc.
The drawback is that ibook is limited to OSX and iOS devices at this time—which is why I will also be making it available as a print-on-demand text (though the interactive content will not obviously be included). The complete text is scheduled to be made available by the end of the academic year and I will be using it as the primary source in my Spring courses of Population Genetics BIOL516 and Landscape Genetics ENVS 692&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RVA Urban Dogwood</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/08/rva-urban-dogwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/08/rva-urban-dogwood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a map of the dogwood we&amp;rsquo;ve sampled in the Fan region of Richmond Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling the GSL Library for OSX</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/07/compiling-the-gsl-library-for-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/07/compiling-the-gsl-library-for-osx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on integrating the Swift language into my analysis workflow but much of what I do involves the GNU Scientific Libraries for matrix analysis and other tools.  Here is a quick tutorial on how to install the GSL library on a clean OSX platform.*It is easiest if you have XCode installed.  You can get this from the App Store for free.  Go download it and install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Download the latest version of the GSL libraries.  You can grab them by:
*Looking for your nearest mirror site listed at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/prep/ftp.html&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/prep/ftp.html&lt;/a&gt; and connecting to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Open the directory
gsl/ where all the versions will be listed.  Scroll down and grab
gsl-latest.tar.gz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Open the terminal (Utilities -&amp;gt; Terminal.app) and type:&lt;br /&gt;
cd ~/Downloads&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Unpack the archive by:&lt;br /&gt;
tar zxvf gsl-latest.tar.gz then
cd gsl-1.16/ (or whatever the version actually was, it will probably be some number larger than 1.16).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Inside that folder will be a README file (which you probably won&amp;rsquo;t read) and an INSTALL file (which you should read).  In that folder it will tell you to:&lt;br /&gt;
./configure then&lt;br /&gt;
make then
sudo make install. This last command will require you to type in your password as it is going to install something into the base system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*All the libraries and header files will be installed into the
/usr/local/ directory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GStudio: An R Package for Spatial Analysis of Marker Data</title>
      <link>http://dyerlab/2015/01/gstudio-an-r-package-for-spatial-analysis-of-marker-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dyerlab/2015/01/gstudio-an-r-package-for-spatial-analysis-of-marker-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the main package that provides data types and routines for spatial analysis of genetic marker data. The previous version is currently available on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;CRAN&lt;/a&gt; and you can install it rom within your R environtment by invoking the command
install.packages(&amp;ldquo;gstudio&amp;rdquo;)
If you want to keep up with the latest developments of this package, you can use the version found on GitHub.  Install it from within R as:
require(devtools)
install_github(&amp;ldquo;dyerlab/gstudio&amp;rdquo;)
and that should get you up-to-date.  You&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a fully working LaTeX install and some other stuff to build it if you fork.
The Users Manual for the package with several examples can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dyerlab.github.io/gstudio/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
I have started a github account for this package, you can get access to the whole codebase read about it on the wiki, and contribute to the project from its repo at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/dyerlab&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dyerlab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
